<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[RC Blogs]]></title>
  <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-18T04:26:45+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Renz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JQUERY vs Javascript]]></title>
    <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/jquery/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-17T09:03:19+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/jquery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>FAQ&rsquo;s</h3>

<p>What is Javascript? JQUERY? And what is the difference between the two? Are there any instances where one is better than the other? These are some of the questions I have asked myself when I was implementing JQUERY to my webpage. Although I have some background in Javascript, the word JQUERY has struck my mind and I was left thinking &ldquo;Just what the heck am I supposed to do with this?&rdquo;. And doing the slider has really answered most of my questions. But first&hellip;</p>

<h3>What is the difference between the two?</h3>

<p>Although at first sight, we may think that they are both entirely different languages or scripts used to run many applications. But then again we should think twice. Javascript is used for interface interactions, game development, web applications and so much more. It makes the user-computer interaction more lively and enjoying. Now imagine Javascript and I mean all better functions of it being compiled into one library that you can use for much FASTER browser-rendering. That is what JQUERY is about. The only difference between the two is that JQUERY is a compiled library of javascript codes which makes coding much easier. Here is an example of a Javascript code:</p>

<p><img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/javascript.png" alt="Javascript" /></p>

<p>And here is an example of a JQuery code:
<img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/jquery.png" alt="JQuery" /></p>

<p>Notice the function of JQuery? If not then I&rsquo;ll tell. JQuery can actually call names, not names to bully, but names of elements present in the document. This is really effective when it comes to classes, since sometimes you will be reffering to a particular element but all elements will be affected, this is where JQuery comes in. You can specifically call functions depending on their names or class or id names. Pretty neat huh?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recreation]]></title>
    <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/04/recreation/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-04T09:15:01+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/04/recreation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Started from scratch</h3>

<p>When I started having my training, I was asked to recreate a website just by looking from the screenshots provided. Below are the screenshots provided to me. Have a look for yourself.
<img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/r1.png" alt="ScreenShot 1" />
<img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/r2.png" alt="ScreenShot 1" />
<img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/r3.png" alt="ScreenShot 1" /></p>

<p>And here are the screenshots when I tried to replicate it.
<img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/dup1.png" alt="Recreate 1" />
<img src="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/images/dup2.png" alt="Recreate 2" /></p>

<p>To be quite honest, the design or the layout of the page, the alignment of certain elements, images and text took more time that when I was coding for the slider. I never was really design oriented hahaha! So anyway please check out my next blog, it will be about the documentation for the code of the slider. Please tune in :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intern's First Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/02/myblog/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T15:40:12+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/02/myblog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>New to the Process!</h3>

<p>Well this is my very first blog, and although I have clearly no idea why it worked sinced all I&rsquo;ve done is that I&rsquo;ve followed the instructions located in <a href = "octopress.org">octopress.org</a>, it seems that I have managed to somehow, create a simple blog.</p>

<h3>Time Management</h3>

<p>I was given this task at around 9:30 in the morning and only seem to work it out at almost 4:00 in the afternoon. Seriously, I have got to get my groove on. Since my skills and abilities are used to Windows OS. I still am really trying to fit in with the Linux OS. I need to fit in, and fast if I really want to learn more.</p>

<h3>What I&rsquo;ve Learned so far</h3>

<p>I know that there are more things to learn in the command line other that directory manipulation, sudo apt-get install etc. But I think from what I know in the command line so far, it will get me through the basics of this operating system. Also I have just finished on the activity I&rsquo;ve been working, the re-creation of a website with a very simple slider and paginator with play and pause buttons which I will be featuring in the next blog I&rsquo;ll be doing. And obviously, I&rsquo;ve learned how to create a simple blog, even though this is only a basic blog, I will study on how to make it more lively.</p>

<hr />

<p align = "right">Best regards to me!</p>


<p align = "right">-Renz Carlo</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Intern]]></title>
    <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/01/the-intern/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T10:10:49+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/01/the-intern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The Intern</h3>

<p>There comes a point in our life that we have to start from the bottom in order to be at the top. Like gamers, you can&rsquo;t be a pro if you hadn&rsquo;t been a beginner. That&rsquo;s the reason on why I have branded myself the intern hahaha! Well asides from the fact that I will only have my OJT experience once, it really adds some finesse to me.</p>

<h3>Renz Carlo Aquino Cabual</h3>

<p>Hello, I am Renz Carlo Aquino Cabual. Residing at 025 Rizal Street Cabanatual City, Nueva Ecija, Philippines. Born on June 17, 1995. 19 Years of age, and currently taking an internship under the supervision of Mr. Efren Lim.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
