<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-04T16:40:30+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recreation]]></title>
    <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/04/recreation/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-04T09:15:01+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/04/recreation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Start from scratch</h3>

<p>When I started having my training, I was asked to recreate a website just by looking from the screenshots provided. Have a look for yourself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intern's First Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/02/myblog/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T15:40:12+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://renzcarlocabs.github.io/blog/2014/12/02/myblog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>New to the Process!</h3>

<p>Well this is my very first blog, and although I have clearly no idea why it worked sinced all I&rsquo;ve done is that I&rsquo;ve followed the instructions located in <a href = "octopress.org">octopress.org</a>, it seems that I have managed to somehow, create a simple blog.</p>

<h3>Time Management</h3>

<p>I was given this task at around 9:30 in the morning and only seem to work it out at almost 4:00 in the afternoon. Seriously, I have got to get my groove on. Since my skills and abilities are used to Windows OS. I still am really trying to fit in with the Linux OS. I need to fit in, and fast if I really want to learn more.</p>

<h3>What I&rsquo;ve Learned so far</h3>

<p>I know that there are more things to learn in the command line other that directory manipulation, sudo apt-get install etc. But I think from what I know in the command line so far, it will get me through the basics of this operating system. Also I have just finished on the activity I&rsquo;ve been working, the re-creation of a website with a very simple slider and paginator with play and pause buttons which I will be featuring in the next blog I&rsquo;ll be doing. And obviously, I&rsquo;ve learned how to create a simple blog, even though this is only a basic blog, I will study on how to make it more lively.</p>

<hr />

<p align = "right">Best regards to me!</p>


<p align = "right">-Renz Carlo</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
